Guide to the Williams Ampère collection, circa 1793-2005.
Williams, L. Pearce, Ampère Collection
- Ampère's secondary chem. thesis (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Sixième Tableau- large photocopy (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Ampère material (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Becky's Recueil and others (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Misc. Ampère-related (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Précise de la Théorie des Phénomènes Électro-dynamiques- Ampère (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Plan de Cours de Matheology microfilm (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Annotated Ampère excerpts and articles (Box 5, Folder 22)
- LPW's notes- Ampère at CUL (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Articles about Ampère (Box 5, Folder 24)
- References to Ampère mss. via correspondence (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Ampère vu par Sainte-beuve, 1837 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Fragments d'un Mémoire sur le magnétisme, 1822 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Typescript of "Decouvert dans les Archives de la Societe D'Emulation de L'ain", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Ampère Mémoire, 1823 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- No box 5, folder 30 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- More photocopies of Ampère mss/letters (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Mémoire (présenté à l'Académie sur 1820)- Ampère, 1820 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Ampère letters; photocopies (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Théorie des phénomènes électrodynamiques- Ampère (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Written notes on location of Ampère works (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Mémoire (de l'Académie)- Ampère, 1828 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Mémoire- Dessaignes, perhaps indicative of Ampère, 1812 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- La recherche en mathématiques édité par Ampère, 1815, 1837 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Académie- letters with remarks by Ampère (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Note sur deux Mémoires lus par Ampère, 1821 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Ampère bibliotheque (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Goupiel on Ampère (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Soc. des Amis d'Ampère (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Note sur une novelle expérience électro-dynamique...- Ampère, 1825 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Collection- Bibliographie, Théorie, Mémoire, Extrait (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Copy of Ampère mss., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Mémoire sur la refraction... Ampère, 1815 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Mémoire sur la refraction... Ampère, 1815 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Démonstration de la relation découverte par Mariotte- Ampère (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Misc. articles, mss., and material locations, 1814 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Notes sur les expériences d'Ampère, 1820 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Bib. de l'Inst (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Bibliographie (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Nature of Electricity and Magnetism, 1824 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Cours de Collège de France; Classification naturelle des sciences (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Mémoire sur l'action exercée par un circuit électro-dynamique, 1826 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Ampère photocopies (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Lettre à Leibig par Faraday, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 58)
- Archived notes from the Academy of the Sciences (Box 5, Folder 59)
- Société Philomatique- Biot, 1815-16 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Secondary- Background (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Misc.- Bib., etc. (Box 5, Folder 62)
- bibliotheque Books (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Ethnologia Europaea, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 64)
- Journal de Physique, de Chimie, d'Histoire Naturelle et des Arts- M.H.-M. Dugrotay de Blainville; Correspondence to Ampère, 1822 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Précis des Eexpériences Faites en Allemagne- Ritter, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 66)
- Nouveau Dictionnaire de Physique- Libes, 1806 (Box 5, Folder 67)
- Archives/Research information from France (Box 5, Folder 68)
- Hofmann research- primarily (Box 5, Folder 69)
- Table of Contents for file on mathematics (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Catalogue on microfilms (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 11-11-209 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Archive listing- Academy of Sciences (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Foreword (Box 6, Folder 5)
- 14/13/250: Notations (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Addt'l untitled notated archives (Box 6, Folder 7)
- 10/10/203 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- 11/11/209: Physics courses (Box 6, Folder 9)
- 14/13/250 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Letter to Hachette by Erman (Box 6, Folder 11)
- 10/10/189: Long document on current-carrying wires (Box 6, Folder 12)
- 10/10/195: Letters- Van Eyck (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Letter to Van Beuk (Box 6, Folder 14)
- 14/13/255: Natural History (Box 6, Folder 15)
- 14/13/250: Molecular electricity (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 14/13/250: Electro-chemical théorie (Box 6, Folder 17)
- 14/13/254: Botany and zoology (Box 6, Folder 18)
- 18/16/277: Engel (Box 6, Folder 19)
- 18/16/281: Reid (Box 6, Folder 20)
- 18/16/281: Pegerando (Paris) (Box 6, Folder 21)
- 18/16/281: Kant (Box 6, Folder 22)
- 18/16/281: Logic (Box 6, Folder 23)
- "Oubli à réparer sur les classifications objectives..." (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Observations of Kant's philosophies (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Note sur le criticisme, et sur le réalisme rational- Planta (Box 6, Folder 26)
- On Kant- not Ampère, perhaps Planta (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Observations on Azais's Memoir (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Physiological and psychological observations on the new doctrine of Professor Gull (Box 6, Folder 29)
- On the limited knowledge that can be obtained of nature (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Work on "Psicologie"- Chart (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Mémoire sur un point de Metaphysique par WDB de Geneve, 1810 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Questions proposed at conference- Sept. 22, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Correspondence from Ampère, Dec 1816 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Brouviller on methaphysical philosophers (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Commission de l'Gustruction publique (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Letter on Lavoisier and chemical nomenclature (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Correspondence with Bredin (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Project d'une langue universelle (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Essai sur la théorie des gluides igniformes (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Principles of Mechanics, 1808 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Rapport sur un ouvrage de Bremontier (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Mémoire- Cuvier, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Note on electrical attraction and repulsion (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Note sur l'action qu'exrce sur un petit aimant cylindrique assujetti..., 1821 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Note sur deux Mémoires lus par Ampère, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Remarks on electrodynamic experiments, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Mémoire sur la nature et l'expression mathématique de la force élémentaire... (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Fragments- look like corrections/additions to recueil (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Third Mémoire on electrodynamic phenomena (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Misc. information (to be filed elsewhere) (Box 6, Folder 51)
- L'ingénieux appareil (de M. de la Rive) de l'auteur de ce Mémoire... (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Mémoire de M. Van der Heyden, Gay-Lussac, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Recherche sur l'intégration des equations aux différentielles partialles (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Various notes on electrodynamics (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Letter (undated) with history of Ampère's earliest electrodynamic discoveries (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Draft- Article for Annales des sciences naturelle, 1824 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Fragments sur le magnétisme (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Note- "Experiences à faire", 1820 (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Resumè in response to royal ordinance naming Ampère to Collège Royal de France (Box 6, Folder 60)
- "Fragments du premier memoir" (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Notice sur de nouvelles recherches de Ampère (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Travaux à faire (Box 6, Folder 63)
- (Misc.) Important hints (Box 6, Folder 64)
- Pour le procès- verbal de la séance, 1835 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Part of a memoir on electrodynamics and a rough draft, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Part o fa paper Ampère gave at the Academy attacking Biot's attack on him, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- Misc. articles (possibly from recueil) (Box 6, Folder 68)
- Note sur la nature de l'électricité, 1820 (Box 6, Folder 69)
- Misc. "Fundamental" documents (Box 6, Folder 70)
- Unpublished memoir on relation of electricity to particles of matter (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Correspondence, 1825 (Box 6, Folder 72)
- Mémoire par M. Dessaignes, 1811 (Box 6, Folder 73)
- Liste des foits- Berger (Box 6, Folder 74)
- "Proof" of carbonates de coude metallique- classification (Box 6, Folder 75)
- De l'essai d'une classification naturelle... (Box 6, Folder 76)
- L'ensemble des phénomènes que presentant les corps... (Box 6, Folder 77)
- Des combinaisons de l'hydrgène et des corps abex les quels il forme des composés gazeux (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Note sue quelques propriétés des atomes- Gaudin, 1831-32 (Box 6, Folder 79)
- Precipitation d'un corps dissous par autres (Box 6, Folder 80)
- "First degree probability of our knowledge"- discourse (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Materiaux du cours au Collège de France, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 82)
- L'analyse de l'intelligence humaine, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Causes de l'imperfection de la faculte d'appercevoir des rapports (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Intro courses in various sciences- théorie (Box 6, Folder 84)
- Resume des lesons sur l'integration des Equatione aux differentielles partielles (Box 6, Folder 85)
- Materiaux du cours au Collège de France, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Letters to Julie (Box 6, Folder 87)
- Letter to Delambre, 1814 (Box 6, Folder 88)
- Letters: Bodmer to Ampère, 1810-11 (Box 6, Folder 89)
- Letters to Ampère, 1807 (Box 6, Folder 90)
- Fragments of biographical importance (Box 6, Folder 91)
- Philomathic society (Box 6, Folder 92)
- Ampère's discharge as a "Requisitionnaire" (Box 6, Folder 93)
- Collection of letters (Box 6, Folder 94)
- Misc. manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 95)
- Lists of people (Box 6, Folder 96)
- Lists on people and ideas (Box 6, Folder 97)
- Drafts of letter to restored Bourbon monarch (Box 6, Folder 98)
- Notes of interest on chemistry (Box 6, Folder 99)
- Chemical notes on experience with carbon dioxide gases (Box 6, Folder 100)
- Observations sur la dissertation...à la géométrie de position- Carnot (Box 6, Folder 101)
- Letter to Ampère from Berthollet (Box 6, Folder 102)
- Notes on the cycloid (Box 6, Folder 103)
- Rapport de crelle (Box 6, Folder 104)
- On variations of calculus (Box 6, Folder 105)
- Research on formulas of calculus and mechanics- Ampère (Box 6, Folder 106)
- Applications of calculus regarding maxima and integrals (Box 6, Folder 107)
- Various notes on probability (Box 6, Folder 108)
- Liste de libres- Bib. de Ampère (Box 6, Folder 109)
- "Divorce" of Ampère's daughter (Box 6, Folder 110)
- Letter to Couvier (Box 6, Folder 111)
- Correspondence to Ampère (Box 6, Folder 112)
- Correspondence de Ballanche (Box 6, Folder 113)
- Misc. Correspondence to Ampère (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Letters to Ampère- mostly from Bodmer (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Delambre et Ampère- Desboves, 1881 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Letters of Julie's(Ampère's wife) former suitor- Dumas (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Plurality of State Positions; Decline of French Science (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Note sur la vie et les travaux de Ampère (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Misc. Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Discours prononcé à l'ouverture du Lycée, after 1815 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Description d'un appareil electrodynamique (Paris), corrections by Ampère, 1825 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Correspondence d'Ampère- each piece marked for provenance (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Chemistry (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Ampère and Babinet- La Chimie de Thompson (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Suite du mémoire sur l'action mutuelle... (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Mémoire lus le 187 bre and following sessions of Acad. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Programme du Cours de Physique (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Chem. bleu- Examen philosophique (Box 7, Folder 16)
- More oversize photocopies of Ampère manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Poisson on magnetism, 1826 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Electrical papers peripheral to Ampère (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Journal d'Ampère (Box 7, Folder 20)
- de Launay- Lettres Inedites Claude-Julien Bredin (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Bib. Inst.- Notes devises (Paris) (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Ampère bibliotheque; Machines and Amperian applications bibliotheque (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Photocopies of Ampère manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Diverse notes on Ampère (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Letters and manuscripts- à Ampère (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Ampère- Lefevre, Gineau (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Ampère articles- Gilbert (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Carton 14 (Brouillons- JJA- Summary (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Essai sur la théorie (Box 7, Folder 30)
- bibliotheque- Ville Lyon, 1823-1824 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Rough Draft- Treatise on Electricity and Magnetism (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Additional photocopied Ampère articles and manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Additional photocopied Ampère articles and manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Misc. Ampère articles, citations, and manuscripts (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Letter- Faraday to Abbé Moigno (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Manuscripts and Notes (Cornell copies)- Ampère (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Contents of Ampère cartons regarding Académie des Sciences (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Lettre de Ampère à Erman (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Lettre de Ampère à Erman (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Ampère Formulae and photocopies of manuscripts (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Search resuults and listings of Ampère documents (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Mémoire sur la Refraction de la Lumière, 1816 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Lettre de Dumas à Ampère, 1820 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Unclassified Ampère citations (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Recherches sur les causes de l'attraction et de la repulsion electrique, 1801 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Considerations sur la Théorie Mathématique de Jeu- Ampère, 1802 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Bibliothèque- les résultats de recherche sur Ampère (Box 8, Folder 13)
- On the nature of light and heat (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Last letters and will of Ampère, 1793 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- L'Americide (metaphorical) (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Draft of account of Ampère's discoveries (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Rapport (misc.) (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Sur les expériences de la Rive (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Correspondence d'Ampère, 1835 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Index of miscellaneous files (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Copies of Ampère's Recueil (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Re: Ampère Letters at Cornell University Library, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Ampère Reprints (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Quelques Lettres Inédites d'Ampère, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Hoffman-Ampère bibliotheque (Box 8, Folder 26)
- See de Launay p. 647 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Notes on Laromiguiére (not by Ampère) (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Ampère on his father's religious faith (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Ampère et Meine de Biràn (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Misc. Ampère Letters, 1833 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Mécanique- Ampère, 1806 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Louis Mallex on Ampère (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Exhaits du Journal de Bredin- on Ampère and other sources, 1804 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Catalogue of LPW Library (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Possible gift of library (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Catalogue of microfilms (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Ampère library books needed (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Ampère letters and others (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Catalogue des Papiers d'Ampère (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Offprints and xeroxes- Ampère (Box 8, Folder 41)
- Important Ampère Notes (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Incomplete list of Ampère publications (Box 8, Folder 43)
- Ampère acts- dupicates (Box 8, Folder 44)
- Recherches sur l'application des formules generales du calcul... (and others, large file)- Ampère, 1805 (Box 8, Folder 45)
- Olin Library (Cornell)- Books of interest (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Photos of Ampère's house (Box 8, Folder 47)
- Misc. Letters and Mss.- Ampère (Box 8, Folder 48)
- More Ampère-related, misc. (Box 8, Folder 49)
- Important- "Autobiographie d'Ampère" (Box 8, Folder 50)
- Ampère's Publications (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Ampère's letters- potentially unpublished (Box 8, Folder 52)
- LPW Catalogue (Box 8, Folder 53)
- Collection of Ampère materials with offprints (Box 8, Folder 54)
- Paragraph by Ampère from Charavay (Paris) (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Addt'l materials by Ampère (Box 8, Folder 56)
- Nouvelles Expériences électro-magnétiques- Ampère, 1821 (Box 8, Folder 57)
- Ampère's outside views (Box 8, Folder 58)
- Bibligraphy (Box 8, Folder 59)
- Philosophy of perception (Box 8, Folder 60)
- Konzeoption einer dynamischen... - Ralph Marks (Box 8, Folder 61)
- Ampère's Letters-1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Ampère's Letters-2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Ampère- Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Ampère's Notes-Bibliography and Misc. Documents (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Ampère- Secondary Education and Arts Background (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Ampère- Early Biography and Early Life, Société des amis, September 1820 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Société philomatique (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Ampère- Restitutional Background (Box 9, Folder 8)
- La Philosophie des Lumières (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Important Articles (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Probability théorie (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Ampère and Chemistry (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Ampère-Couppier Letters (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Manuscripts- Ampère (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Interrogation of Jean-Jacques Ampère (Box 10, Folder 4)
- La Rive, Auguste, 1829-34 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Ampère, P.- execution; Letter of Recommendation of André-Marie Ampère, 1793; 1802 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Excerpt of Peuple de Lyon- Balleydier, 1845 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- De-Lewnay- Les Trois Ampère, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Oersted Articles (Box 10, Folder 9)
- General Reference Information; Lettres de Gérando, 1880 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Maine de Biran, Ampère, and de Gérando, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Camille Jordan, 1826 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Ampère- Miscellaneous, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Background information on Lyon; Ampère on Electrodynamics (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Ampère and Kant (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Others on Ampère (Box 10, Folder 16)
- List of Ampère's Publications on Mechanical Engineering (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Ampère's Philosophies in Chart Form (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Académie de Sciences- Paris (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous articles on electrodynamics and mathematics- 'Important' (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Contemporary Electromagnetism (in Europe), 1800-40 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Kant (Box 11, Folder 3)
- A World on Paper- E. Bellone (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Jacobism and the Revolt of Lyon- W.D. Edmonds, 1789-93 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Additional (labeled non-essential) Background Information (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Diverse Arts- Peripheral- on Electromagnetism (Box 11, Folder 7)
- The Rise and Fall of Laplacian Physics- R. Fox (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Vaysse de Villiers, 1813 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Arago's Wheel- non-Ampère (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Botany (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Recherches sur la Cause de l'Electricité Voltaique- de la Rive, 1834 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Recherches sur les Propriétés des Courants Magnéto-Electriques, 1837 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Ampère's Retirement (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Relevant to Ampère (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Théorie du Monde et des Etres Organisés Suivant les Principes- Mesmer, 1784 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Experimenta circa effectum Conflictus Electrici in Acum Magnetism- Oersted (Box 11, Folder 17)
- La découverte par Ampère de l'électrodynamique- Mallez, 1944-45 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Des Sigues- Degerando (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Table par Ordre de Matières, 1878 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Main de Biran (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Crystallography (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Frankel on Biot (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Davy and Electricity, 1821 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Mathematics, Philosophy of Physics (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous Ampère Reprints (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Electricity and Magnetism- non-Ampère (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Collège de France Equipment- Laboratory, 1821 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous Important Articles on Ampère (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Photos of Ampère's Charts (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Ampère e le théorie della natura del color- Sebastiani, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Speculative Grammars of the Middle Ages- Bursill-Hall, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Course on elementary mathematics (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Philosophy- Kant, Cousin, Ampère, Maine de Biran (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Roux-Bordier Boddmer (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Traité élémentaires d'Arithmétique (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous papers- Paris (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Daburon on the Calculus of Differential Equations (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Position Geometry (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Precise Integration Examples, 1869 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Definitions of Functions (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Principes de l'analyse (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Recherches Variées (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Introduction to Force Equilibrium (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Notions sur les machines (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Mémoire sur la nature et l'exp. mathématiques (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Proofs (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Mémoire sur phénomènes électrodynamiques (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Error in work- Change of electromagnetic to electrodynamic (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Additional note fragments (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Notes on electromagnetic motions- Oersted (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Notes on Electromagnetism (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Ampère's papers- Cart. 5, Chap. 4 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Tables des Articles (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Notes on conduction (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Excerpt from work by Van Beck (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Influences de cer faits (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Ampère's papers- Cart. 10, Chap. 10 (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Electric nature of molecules (Box 12, Folder 25)
- Circular magnet diagram (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Miscellaneous on Chemistry (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous on Electricity (Box 12, Folder 28)
- On Chemistry- Important (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Carton 12, Chapter 11, Chem 216 (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Carton 12, Chapter 11, Chem 237 (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Carton 13, Chapter 12, Chem 229 (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Carton 13, Chapter 12, Chem 230: Refraction (Box 12, Folder 33)
- Carton 13, Chapter 12, Chem 236 (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Carton 14, Chapter 10, Chem 207- On nomenclature of acids, 1815 (Box 12, Folder 35)
- Carton 14, Chapter 15, Chem 245- Molecular Weights (Box 12, Folder 36)
- Carton 14, Chapter 13, Chem 251 (Paris) (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Carton 16, Chapter 16, Chem 263 (Box 12, Folder 38)
- Carton 16, Chapter 16, Chem 264 (Box 12, Folder 39)
- Carton 20, Chapter 18, Chem 302 (three folders on course topics) (Box 12, Folder 40)
- Carton 28- Outline of course in mathematics (Box 12, Folder 41)
- Carton 29- Class of subject broullons (non-classes) (Box 12, Folder 42)
- Carton 29 (non-classes)- Lecons d'Analyse (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Carton 31- Apparatus Diagrams (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Carton 30- Notes on classification of knowledge (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Carton 32 (non-classes) (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Cartons 30-32- Notes on chart, Apparatus, Brouillous (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Carton 24 (non-classes)- Brouillous de Chimie (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Carton 34- Ampère's broken arm and theoretical chemistry (Paris) (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Carton 37 (non-classes) (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Arago's Wheel and Universal Magnetism, 1824-37 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Tables of Contents (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Kant in France (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Carton 35 (non-classes)- Chart of the Mind, Psychology and Classification (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Cartons 27-29- Treatise on Mathematics, 1816 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Cartons 30-31- Classification Charts, Neologisms, unclear Mathematics (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 189- Various Notes (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 208- on the electrical nature of molecules (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 205- fragment of a memoir magnetism (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 205- "Mes 3 grandes choses sout" (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 205- Research on the causes of attraction in electric repulsion (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 205- Brouillous on salts and chemistry (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Drafts of various articles, 1824 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Carton 10, Chapter 10, Chem 189- Various notes on electromagnetism, 1824 (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Article on electrodynamics- metallic movement, voltage, and conductors- Ampère, 1826 (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Carton 9, Chapter 10, Chem 182- Electrodynamic experiments, "Interesting but difficult" (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Various folders with articles on general Electrodynamics, 1820 (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Carton 27 (non-classes)- Drafts of articles (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Bibliotheque de l'Institut (Box 13, Folder 27)